KYLA FITZPATRICK

San Diego, CA 92103 | Phone: 704.748.3653 | Email: kfitzpatrick44@gmail.com GitHub: github.com/KylaFitzpatrick | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/kylaannefitzpatrick

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER & QA ENGINEER

Front-End Web Developer leveraging experience in QA to build a more coherent user experience on the web. Known as a critical thinker when developing apps, with a focus on web development. Advocate for the user-experience for each project. Applied aspects of QA and agile development on various teams where I worked with Developers, Product Managers and other QA colleagues to deliver new user-focused features on time. Driven to hone skills in the future as a web developer to deliver more engaging user experiences on the web.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: SQL, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, CSS, CSS3, HTML5, JSON

Database: MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase

Other: Heroku, Git, Bash, Microsoft Office Suite, JIRA, TFS, FogBugz, HP Quality Center,

Bootstrap, Materialize CSS

PROJECTS

Youtify - kylafitzpatrick.github.io/Youtify/ | github.com/KylaFitzpatrick/Youtify Full-stack web app that allows user to vote on their favorite song or video

- Worked with a team of four in creating a full-stack web app that uses Spotiy API and YouTube API to display songs and videos users can vote on.
- Tools used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase, Spotify API, Bootstrap, YouTube API

WordGuess - <u>kylafitzpatrick.github.io/Word-Guess/</u> | <u>github.com/KylaFitzpatrick/Word-Guess/</u> *Web app that generates a random animal word*

- Built a word guess app game that allows users to guess a randomly selected animal name and if the user guesses the animal correctly a YouTube video of the animal displays.
- Tools used: HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript

SF Scraper - <u>sf-scraper.herokuapp.com</u> | <u>github.com/KylaFitzpatrick/SF_Scraper</u> *Full-stack web app that scrapes the SF Chronicle for news articles*

- Designed an app that allows users to scrape articles from the SF Chronicle so they can save articles as well as attach notes to the saved articles
- Tools used: Node.JS, Express, MongoDB, HTML5, CSS, Materialize CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and Handlebars

EXPERIENCE

CoStar Group Software Engineer in Test

Austin, TX 2019-2019

- Contributed to creating and maintaining UI automated test scripts in an Agile System Development Life Cycle (SDLC)
- Utilized Visual Studio and Selenium to build automated tests suites as well as debugging test scripts

- Experienced in documenting and tracking bugs in TFS in collaboration with developers, product on an agile team
- Competencies: automation skills, TFS skills, Visual Studio skills

ESO Junior Software Development Engineer in Test

Austin, TX 2018-2018

- Executed manual, smoke, and regression testing for three fire department applications in Agile SDLC
- Leveraged Postman for API testing as well as utilizing Sauce Labs for cross browser and device testing
- Experienced in documenting and tracking bugs in Jira in collaboration with developers and product
- Competencies: Sauce Labs skills, Jira skills, Postman skills

CoStar Group Quality Assurance Engineer

Austin, TX 2016-2018

- Contributed to creating and maintaining UI automated test scripts in an Agile System
 Created and executed manual and automated test cases across Land of America
 network 153 sites
- Learned basics of automation testing utilizing Visual Studio, Selenium, SpecFlow, Git Extensions, and C#
- Experience in functional testing in Firefox, Internet Explorer, Chrome as well as on iOS and Android devices
- Competencies: C# skills, Selenium skills, Git skills

CoStar Group Associate Quality Assurance Engineer

San Francisco, CA

2016-2016

- Utilize Test Manager to create and execute test cases according to business requirements in an Agile System Development Life Cycle (SDLC)
- Collaborate with developers and designers to ensure bugs are documented and resolved in Test Manager
- Experience in functional testing in Firefox, Internet Explorer, Chrome as well as on iOS and Android devices
- Competencies: detail orientation skills, communication skills, SQL skills

CITCO Junior Quality Assurance Analyst

Charlotte, NC 2014-2015

- Analyzed test scenarios and cases in HP quality center conforming to user requirement specification documents in addition to defect logging during functional testing in a timeline driven environment
- Liaise with developers and business teams to ensure testing accuracy for over 4 hedge fund applications
- Developed as well as executed ad hoc and regression tests in all stages of an Agile System Development Life Cycle (SDLC)
- Competencies developed: organization skills, financial skills, analytical skills

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

University of Texas – Austin, TX

A 6-month intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in MongoDB, React, Express, Node.js, and JavaScript

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, International Business The University of North Carolina at Charlotte– Charlotte, NC